# **PARAG PATEL**

Somerset, NJ 08873

Phone: (609)-271-4217 | Email: paragpatel201@yahoo.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/parag-patel-6960b625

Github: https://paragpatel201.github.io/

#### SUMMARY

Experienced Brand Manager with G-III Apparel Group with exceptional communications and leadership skills. Currently in training for data analysis with a background in management and skills in Excel, VBA, Python, and SQL from Rutgers Data Science Bootcamp. Insatiable intellectual curiosity and ability to locate hidden logic within large sets of structured, semi-structured, and raw data. Expert at leveraging background and skill set to support detailed and efficient analysis. Recently completed a project with a team of six using data sets from epa.gov and cdc.gov on air pollution and health effects. Utilized Python, Pandas, and Jupyter notebook to visualize the comparison of air pollutants to health causes in the tri-state area from 2006 to 2018. My analytical problem-solving abilities combined with strengths in collaborating across diverse groups, makes me a valuable addition to any team.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Tools:** Advanced Excel, Pivot Tables, VBA Scripting, Fundamental Statistics, Modeling, Forecasting, Python Programming, Python 3, NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, API Interactions, Social Media Mining, Databases, Front–End Web Visualization, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Dashboarding, JavaScript Charting D3.js, Geomapping with Leaflet.js, Business Intelligence Software, Tableau, Advanced Topics, Big Data Analytics with Hadoop, Machine Learning

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, ETL

#### **PROJECTS**

# Air Pollution in the Tristate & Nationwide: Trends & Health Effects | https://github.com/paragpatel201/Project-2-.git

- Continue to research the trends in outdoor air quality, based on established air quality indicators, from the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) in Tristate and Nationwide.
- We created data visualizations using Stacked Bar, Multi-Series Line Charts, donut chart and AQI Maps.

### ETL Project | https://github.com/paragpatel201/ETL-Project.git

- Responsible for Web scrapping Walmart website taking information needed for the project and convert into json file to upload on mongo DB
- My SQL, MongoDB, Python (Visual Studio Code), Web Scrapping, Jupyter notebook, Excel, Debugging/Problem Solving

## Project- Air Pollution and Health effects | https://github.com/paragpatel201/Project-1.git

- Examined the trends in outdoor air quality, based on established air quality indicators, from the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (EPA). We also examined potential trends in the temporal associations between air pollutants and specific health effects in humans
- Python (Visual Studio Code), Jupyter notebook, Excel, Data Exploration and Clean-up Process, EPA AQI Data, EPA Individual air pollutant data (gases)

- Utilized zip\_download function to download the large datasets for data more than a decade
- Utilized API and Seaborn to create heat maps for ozone levels in tristate by county

#### EXPERIENCE

# Brand Manager (Northeast Region) G-III Apparel Group

2015-Present New York, NY

Analyze sales and inventory on a daily, weekly, monthly, quarterly and annual basis to track and determine the needs of the business; monitor stock levels, sales plans, and assortments. Analyze sales data to update a brand or category portfolio, determine new products and delete underperforming products. Track consumer and market insights by reviewing metrics such as sales volume, market share, profit projections, pricing and distribution, and by conducting consumer research

### Key Accomplishments:

- Manage 18 focus doors at a combined volume of \$12 million- increased 23% as of fiscal year 2019
- Support the launch for DKNY and Donna Karen handbag brand for two major accounts

# Merchandising Team Manager Macy's

2012-2015 New Jersey/New York

Partnered with executive team to execute analysis of merchandising reports to review business results and take appropriate action to capitalizing on business strengths and impact deficiencies. Dealt with direct merchandise receipt placement, replenishment and sales promotion set-up; partnered with our executive team to plan and execute floor/fixture moves, merchandise placement and presentations.

### Key Accomplishments:

- Managed total store volume of \$28 million with a 19% growth as of fiscal year 2015
- Managed \$12 Million-dollar volume, part of expansion to \$18 Million-dollar dress shirt business in HSQ

#### **EDUCATION**

Data Science Bootcamp Certificate: Rutgers University, Somerset, NJ.

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Excel, VBA, Python, R, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data, and Machine Learning.

**Associate Degree in Business Administration: Atlantic Cape Community College**, Mays Landing, NJ.